Toyan George Green

Birmingham, England, UK

toyangreen@gmail.com

+44 (0) 7511 934 305

uk.linkedIn.com/in/toyangreen

www.toyangreen.com

TL; DR

A highly adaptable software developer, looking to transition into the games industry. I have 4 years of professional experience in an Agile, test driven environment and currently studying an MSc in video game development. I am seeking a position that will allow me to apply and grow my existing skills and challenge me to develop further. I am resourceful, self-aware, and have proven myself to work well in a team. Most importantly, I love video games!

SKILLS

- Languages: C#, C++, JavaScript
- Experienced use of version control systems (Git, Perforce, Plastic SCM, SVN)
- Automated testing (TDD & BDD) and continuous integration
- Ability to highlight problems and risks, and identify potential solutions
- Proven ability to rapidly cross train to meet requirements
- Familiar with various game engines/frameworks (Unity/Unreal/MonoGame/Cocos2d-x)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

September 2015 – September 2019

Rock Solid Knowledge, Bristol

Worked on a variety of projects in a rapidly expanding environment, whilst continually learning new skills to deliver the best solutions. Worked with clients on legacy and greenfield legacy projects, and on internal projects that fulfilled the needs of a growing company. Shipped 4 projects, whilst also contributing to other projects and research tasks.

3D Content Developer

June 2015 - July 2015

Ishida Europe Ltd, Birmingham

Unity development position. Worked as part of a small team to create "Ishida Expert" training software and simulations.

EDUCATION

MSc Video Game Development

September 2019 - Present

Birmingham City University

Working as a programmer within multidisciplinary teams to deliver a 2D platformer game for PC using Cocos2d-x, and a 3d arena fighting game using Unreal Engine and PlayStation 4 Devkits.

BSc (Hons) Computer Games Technology (2:1)

September 2012 – May 2015

Birmingham City University

Dissertation: The use of persuasion in video games

2 A-Levels (Computing, Sociology),

September 2009 – June 2012

3 AS-Levels (Physics, Maths, Chemistry),

Welsh Baccalaureate

St David's Catholic College

POSITIONS OF RESPONSIBILITY AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Certified Scrum Master
- A designated fire marshal at Rock Solid Knowledge.
- The student representative for The Heights student accommodation, Birmingham.
- A peer mentor within the learning support department of St David's College. I supported the studies of less able students that required extra assistance.

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

I really enjoy cooking. Sometimes it's relaxing, sometimes it's stressful, often results in something tasty.

I love to learn. I try to always carry a book with me, and I make use of online learning platforms to improve my skillset.

Music is my second passion in life. I go to as many concerts as I can, and often find myself travelling up and down the country for a chance to see my favourite bands.

FAVOURITE GAMES

Super Mario World, Toy Story 2: Buzz Lightyear to the Rescue, Jak and Daxter: The Precursor Legacy, Restistance: Fall of Man, Burnout Paradise, RockBand, Uncharted, Horizon Zero Dawn, God of War

REFERENCES

Excellent references available on request